Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking a little bit about, well, kind of girly things.
我是Catherine，今天我们聊点……嗯，有点女孩子气的话题。
That's right.
没错。
We've talked about guys' shoes, women's shoes.
我们聊过男鞋、女鞋。
So now we're going to talk about another aspect of women's accessories.
所以现在我们要聊聊女性配饰的另一个方面。
We're going to talk about makeup.
我们要聊聊化妆品。
Okay, so we're wearing makeup today.
好，所以我们今天在化妆。
Actually we're buying makeup at the store.
其实我们是在商店里买化妆品。
I never even knew there were so many kinds of makeup.
我从来不知道有这么多化妆品。
So we're going to learn all about these in today's dialogue.
所以我们会在今天的对话中了解所有这些。
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's go grab a bite to eat.
我们去吃点东西吧。
Yeah, me too.
是啊，我也饿了。
Oh, can we stop at the shop really fast?
哦，我们能快速去趟商店吗？
I lost my makeup bag at the airport and I want to pick up a few things.
我的化妆包在机场丢了，我想买点东西。
Will you take long?
要很久吗？
No, five minutes.
不会，五分钟。
I promise.
我保证。
Come on.
快点吧。
We've been here for almost an hour.
我们在这儿都快一个小时了。
I thought you said you were only going to get a few things.
我以为你说你只买几样东西。
How long does it take you to pick out a lipstick and some nail polish?
挑一支口红和指甲油要花多长时间？
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
You have no idea what you're talking about.
你根本不知道你在说什么。
Just for my eyes I have to get eyeliner, an eyelash curler, eye shadow, an eyebrow pencil,
光是我的眼睛，我就得买眼线笔、睫毛夹、眼影、眉笔，
and mascara.
还有睫毛膏。
Then I need to get foundation, liquid foundation.
然后我还需要粉底，液体粉底。
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇，哇，哇。
Are you nuts?
你脑子坏掉了吗？
How much is all this going to cost?
这些总共要花多少钱？
I'm looking at the price of each one of these little things and it's outrageous.
我看了一下这些小东西每个的价格，简直离谱。
This is basically a crayon.
这基本上就是根蜡笔。
What about you?
那你呢？
You spend as much money or more on your razors, aftershave, cologne, and gel.
你在剃须刀、须后水、古龙水和发胶上花的钱一样多，甚至更多。
Not to mention how much you spend on clothes and...
更别提你在衣服上花了多少……
Fine.
好吧。
Get the stupid $30 crayon.
买那根30美元的破蜡笔吧。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So obviously we're getting a lot of things for this girl, a lot of makeup.
所以很明显，我们给这个女孩买了很多东西，很多化妆品。
So I think there are a couple of things that we may not know about.
所以我觉得可能有一些我们不太了解的东西。
So let's take a look at them now on Language Takeaway.
那我们现在就在“语言小贴士”环节来看看它们。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
So the first thing we're talking about today is a basic.
今天我们聊的第一样东西是个基础款。
Most women carry this around in their purses.
大多数女性都会把它放在包里随身携带。
It's called lipstick.
它叫口红。
That's right.
没错。
And as you said, this is a pretty basic thing.
就像你说的，这是个很基础的东西。
It's the kind of like paint that you put on your lips.
它就像涂在嘴唇上的颜料。
And it's called a lipstick because it looks like a little stick.
它叫口红，因为它看起来像一根小棒子。
Right, and you turn it with your fingers and it comes up and then you turn it again and
对，你用手指转一下它就出来，再转一下它就缩回去，基本上是为了避免碰到包里所有东西。
it goes down, basically keeping it from touching all of the things in your purse.
没错。
That's right.
所以是口红。
So lipstick.
嗯，除了这个，我们还有指甲油。
And well, apart from this, we also have nail polish.
这也是女士们很喜欢的，用来把指甲涂成某种颜色。
And this is also very popular with the ladies when you paint your nails a certain color.
没错。
That's right.
所以“polish”基本上就是任何能让东西变亮的东西。
So polish is basically anything that makes something shiny.
它是你加在表面上的东西。
It's something that you add to surfaces.
所以你可以给木桌打蜡。
So you could add polish to wood on a table.
但在这里，我们把它涂在指甲上。
But in this case, we're putting it on our nails.
也就是手指甲或脚趾甲。
That is fingernails or toenails.
所以是指甲油。
So it's nail polish.
好，非常好。
Alright, very good.
现在我们开始聊具体的东西。
And now we're getting into the specific things.
很多女性用在眼睛上的化妆品。
A lot of makeup that women use on their eyes.
比如，她说的第一样东西，她需要买眼线笔。
So for example, the first thing she said, she needs to get an eyeliner.
好，所以眼线笔基本上就是一支铅笔。
Okay, so eyeliner is basically a pencil.
这就是那个男的取笑她的东西。
This is what the guy is making fun of her about.
他说那只是根铅笔或蜡笔，用来画眼睛。
He says it's just a pencil or a crayon for your eye.
所以基本上，你用它在上眼皮或下眼皮上画一条线。
And so basically, you use it to draw a line on the top or the bottom of your eye, your
好，所以是的，它看起来有点像记号笔，有黑色和不同颜色，然后你在眼睛周围画小线条，让眼睛更突出。
eyelid.
所以它叫眼线笔。
Okay, so yeah, it kind of looks like a marker and it comes, I think, black and different
好，现在我们还有睫毛夹。
colors and then you paint little lines around your eyes to make them more pronounced.
而且，我觉得这对女士们来说很重要。
So it's called an eyeliner.
是啊，不过不是每个人都用这个。
Okay, and now we have an eyelash curler.
这是个有点吓人的工具。
And also, I think this is very important for the ladies.
它看起来好像会把你的眼睛戳出来。
Yeah, well not everyone uses this.
没错。
It's a little bit of a scary instrument.
它看起来好像会把你的眼睛戳出来。
It looks like it might pop your eye out.
It's something you use on your eyelashes.
这是用在你的睫毛上的东西。
So those are the hairs that come off of your eye.
所以那些就是你眼睛上长出来的毛发。
And basically, you use this to make them curly or to make them seem a bit longer and prettier.
基本上，你用这个来让它们卷曲，或者让它们看起来更长更漂亮。
So an eyelash curler is something that, it's almost like a press or something for your
所以睫毛夹是一种东西，它几乎就像一个按压工具，用来处理你的
eyelashes.
睫毛。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And well, now that we've got that covered, we move on to eye shadow.
好了，既然我们已经讲完了那个，我们接着来说眼影。
And I think this goes on your eyelid, right?
我觉得这个是用在眼皮上的，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Some people make it go further.
有些人会把它涂得更远。
They put it on their face above their eyelid, but that's a little bit crazy.
他们会把它涂在眼皮上方的脸上，但那有点疯狂。
I think eye shadow generally goes, like you said, on your eyelid.
我觉得眼影通常就像你说的，涂在眼皮上。
And it can be in many different colors.
而且它有很多不同的颜色。
So blue, pink, red, whatever.
比如蓝色、粉色、红色，随便什么。
People sometimes go crazy with eye shadow.
人们有时候用眼影会变得很疯狂。
Okay.
好的。
And now what about an eyebrow pencil?
那眉笔呢？
This is basically a pencil for filling in or for coloring your eyebrows.
这基本上是一种用来填充或给眉毛上色的笔。
Sometimes people like to make their eyebrows look darker or thicker.
有时候人们想让眉毛看起来更黑或更浓密。
And so they use this pencil.
所以他们就用这种笔。
It's usually brown or black.
它通常是棕色或黑色的。
And they use it on their eyebrows.
他们把它用在眉毛上。
So we've picked up a lot of vocab here related to your eye.
所以我们学到了很多和眼睛相关的词汇。
For example, an eyelash, your eyelid.
比如，睫毛，你的眼皮。
Now we're talking about the eyebrows, which are the hairs on top, more or less around
现在我们说到眉毛，那是额头上面大概
your forehead.
周围的毛发。
And now we also have another type of makeup called mascara.
现在我们还有另一种化妆品叫睫毛膏。
This is another basic.
这是另一种基础品。
So like we said earlier, lipstick is something you almost always find in a woman's purse.
就像我们之前说的，口红是几乎每个女人包里都能找到的东西。
Well, mascara is another one of those things.
嗯，睫毛膏也是其中之一。
Almost everybody wears mascara.
几乎每个人都用睫毛膏。
This is kind of like a brush for your eyelashes and it paints them a different color.
这有点像一把刷子，用来刷睫毛，把它们涂成不同的颜色。
So most women wear black or brown and it makes your eyelashes look really long.
所以大多数女性用黑色或棕色，它能让你的睫毛看起来很长。
Oh, okay.
哦，好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So this is kind of like paint for your eyelashes.
所以这有点像给睫毛上色。
And now moving away from your eyelashes, we're going to have, we're buying also some foundation
现在离开睫毛，我们要买一些粉底
and liquid foundation.
和液体粉底。
Okay.
好的。
So foundation is just a kind of base for your face.
所以粉底只是你脸部的一种基础底妆。
So foundation, like a building, is the very bottom.
所以粉底，就像建筑一样，是最底层。
Well, in this case, it's something that you put on your cheeks, on your face in general,
嗯，在这种情况下，它是你涂在脸颊、整个脸上、
on your forehead to kind of smooth your skin out and make it look all the same color or
额头上，用来平滑皮肤，让肤色看起来一致或
the same texture.
质地相同的东西。
And so foundation can be like we see here, either a powder, which is kind of like a dry
所以粉底可以像我们这里看到的，要么是粉末，一种干燥的
substance, or you can use liquid foundation, which is like it says, liquid.
物质，要么你可以用液体粉底，就像名字说的，是液体。
It's almost like a thick cream.
它几乎像一种浓稠的乳霜。
All right.
好的。
So foundation is, as you said, I guess you just want to make your skin look the same
所以粉底就像你说的，我猜你只是想让皮肤看起来颜色一致、
color, the same texture, because obviously not everyone's skin is perfect.
质地相同，因为显然不是每个人的皮肤都完美。
We all have some spots maybe, or some different color on our face.
我们可能都有一些斑点，或者脸上有些颜色不均。
You say we like you wear foundation too.
你说我们好像你也用粉底。
Do you wear makeup, Marco?
你用化妆品吗，Marco？
Well, I mean, we as people because, you know.
嗯，我的意思是，我们作为人，因为你知道。
All right.
好的。
No, no, no, no, none of this makeup for me, although I have used an eyelash curler once.
不，不，不，不，这些化妆品我都不用，虽然我用过一次睫毛夹。
That's scary.
那真吓人。
Well, my friends dared me to, so okay.
嗯，我的朋友激我，所以好吧。
And you loved it.
而且你很喜欢。
Of course.
当然。
Now I use it all the time.
现在我一直在用。
No, no.
不，不。
But what I do use is now things related to guys.
但我用的是一些和男士相关的东西。
So for example, the girlfriend was saying, well, you buy razors and aftershave.
比如，女朋友说，嗯，你买剃须刀和须后水。
So what are these things?
这些东西是什么？
Well, razors aren't just a guy thing.
嗯，剃须刀不只是男士用的东西。
Everyone can have a razor.
每个人都可以有剃须刀。
It's basically a blade, like a very sharp piece of metal that you use to cut hair.
它基本上是一个刀片，一种非常锋利的金属片，用来剃毛发。
So the hair on your legs, the hair on your face, these are things that you cut with a
所以腿上的毛、脸上的毛，这些都是你用剃须刀
razor.
剃掉的东西。
And men use razors to shave their faces, shave their chins or above their lip.
男士用剃须刀刮脸、刮下巴或嘴唇上方。
All right.
好的。
And well, actually, after we shave our beard, we put on a little bit of aftershave, which
嗯，实际上，刮完胡子后，我们会涂一点须后水，它
is basically kind of like alcohol that smells really nice.
基本上是一种闻起来很香的酒精。
That's right, because shaving can actually hurt your skin or the hairs under your skin
没错，因为刮胡子实际上会伤害皮肤，或者皮肤下的毛发
can become really itchy or irritated.
会变得很痒或发炎。
And so aftershave helps make everything feel better.
所以须后水有助于让一切感觉更好。
Okay.
好的。
Well, and sometimes we also use a little bit of cologne to smell nice.
嗯，有时候我们也会用一点古龙水来闻起来香。
So women usually wear perfume, which is, you know, the perfumes like CK and Hugo Boss and
所以女性通常用香水，比如CK和Hugo Boss这些香水，还有
all that stuff, as well as for guys, it's usually called cologne.
所有这些，还有男士用的，通常叫古龙水。
Okay, that's right.
没错，是这样。
It's an important difference there because we don't say perfume for guys and we don't
这个区别很重要，因为我们不说男士用香水，也不说
say cologne for girls.
女士用古龙水。
So women wear perfume, like you said, but men wear cologne.
所以女士用香水，就像你说的，但男士用古龙水。
And this word is very funny looking.
这个词看起来很有趣。
It ends with, it's spelled C-O-L-O-G-N-E.
它结尾拼写是C-O-L-O-G-N-E。
So you don't really say the G, it's not cologna.
所以G不发音，不是cologna。
Right.
对。
It's cologne.
是cologne。
And it's something that you put on your neck or your face to smell really good if you're
这是你涂在脖子或脸上，让自己闻起来很香的东西，如果你是
a man.
男士的话。
Exactly.
没错。
And finally, if you have long hair or maybe you have very spiky hair like I do, you need
最后，如果你有长发，或者像我这样有很尖的头发，你需要
to wear a little bit of gel to kind of give your head a little bit of shape.
用一点发胶来给头发塑形。
That's right.
对。
So gel is actually the name of a kind of substance.
所以发胶实际上是一种物质的名称。
It's not liquid, but it's not hard either.
它不是液体，但也不是硬的。
And it's basically thick like paste that you put in your hair to keep it in one place.
它基本上像糊状物一样稠，涂在头发上让它固定在一个位置。
Yeah, it makes your hair become a little bit hard or it keeps your hairstyle in for a long
是的，它让头发变硬一点，或者让发型保持很久。
time.
时间到了。
That's right.
没错。
All right, so a lot of vocab here, a lot of things that we've picked up.
好了，这里有很多词汇，很多我们学到的东西。
Why don't we go back, review all this great vocab on our dialogue for today.
我们为什么不回顾一下，复习今天对话里的这些好词汇呢？
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's go grab a bite to eat.
我们去吃点东西吧。
Yeah, me too.
是啊，我也饿了。
Oh, can we stop at the shop really fast?
哦，我们能很快去趟商店吗？
I lost my makeup bag at the airport and I want to pick up a few things.
我在机场丢了化妆包，想买点东西。
Will you take long?
你会花很长时间吗？
No, five minutes.
不会，五分钟。
I promise.
我保证。
Come on, we've been here for almost an hour.
拜托，我们在这儿都快一个小时了。
I thought you said you're only going to get a few things.
我以为你说你只买几样东西。
How long does it take you to pick out a lipstick and some nail polish?
挑一支口红和指甲油要花你多长时间？
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
You have no idea what you're talking about.
你根本不知道你在说什么。
First for my eyes, I have to get eyeliner, an eyelash curler, eye shadow, an eyebrow
首先是我的眼睛，我得买眼线笔、睫毛夹、眼影、眉笔，
pencil, and mascara.
还有睫毛膏。
Then I need to get foundation, liquid foundation.
然后我需要粉底，液体粉底。
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇，哇，哇。
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
How much is all this going to cost?
这些总共要花多少钱？
I'm looking at the price of each one of these little things and it's outrageous.
我看着这些小东西每个的价格，简直离谱。
This is basically a crayon.
这基本上就是根蜡笔。
What about you?
那你呢？
You spend as much money or more on your razors, aftershave, cologne, and gel.
你在剃须刀、须后水、古龙水和啫喱上花的钱也不少，甚至更多。
Not to mention how much you spend on clothes and-
更别提你在衣服上花的钱了，还有——
Fine, get the stupid $30 crayon.
好吧，买那根30美元的蠢蜡笔吧。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we're going to take a look at three short phrases that we've picked out for you
现在我们要看看三个简短短语，我们为你挑选出来的。
on Fluency Builder.
在流利度提升环节。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升环节。
So this first phrase is something that we almost always say with our friends or family
第一个短语是我们和朋友或家人在一起时几乎总会说的。
when we're hungry, we're shopping.
当我们饿了，在购物的时候。
Sometimes you're outside and you just really want to eat.
有时候你在外面，真的很想吃东西。
You say, hey, let's grab a bite to eat.
你会说，嘿，我们去随便吃点东西吧。
That's right.
没错。
It's a very natural colloquial way of saying, let's go get something to eat or let's go
这是一种非常自然的口语化说法，意思是“我们去弄点吃的”或者“我们去”。
eat something.
吃点东西。
So it could be small, it could be a snack like an ice cream, but it can also be dinner.
所以它可以是小份的，比如冰淇淋这样的小吃，但也可以是一顿正餐。
So hey, do you want to go grab a bite to eat sometime?
嘿，那你想不想什么时候一起去吃点东西？
That means, hey, you want to go have lunch or dinner sometime?
意思是，嘿，你想什么时候一起去吃个午餐或晚餐吗？
Very good.
很好。
So the phrase is grab a bite or go grab a bite to eat.
所以这个短语是“grab a bite”或者“go grab a bite to eat”。
So a bite can be a noun, like a thing, like a piece of food that you eat, but it can also
所以，"a bite" 可以是一个名词，比如指你吃的一口食物，但它也可以
be a verb, to bite, like the dog bites the man.
是一个动词，表示“咬”，比如狗咬人。
And so you have to be careful with this one.
所以这个你得小心点。
In this case, it's a noun.
在这种情况下，它是一个名词。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And well, she wanted to first go to the store and she said, I want to pick up a few things.
嗯，她先想去商店，还说“我想买点东西”。
Well, usually when you pick something up, you take it from a table or from the ground.
嗯，通常当你拿起某样东西时，你是从桌子上或地上把它拿起来的。
But in this case, it means to buy something because you can't just pick something up in
但在这种情况下，它的意思是购买某物，因为你不能随便拿起就走。
a store and then walk away.
走进一家店，然后转身就走。
You have to pay for it.
你必须为此付钱。
So for example, you can say, when you come home, can you pick up a carton of milk?
例如，你可以说，你回家的时候，能顺便买一盒牛奶吗？
So that means, can you buy some milk on your way home?
所以，你回家的路上能买点牛奶吗？
It doesn't mean, can you take some from someone else or steal some.
这并不意味着你可以从别人那里拿一些或者偷一些。
Exactly.
没错。
All right, so to pick something up, to buy, to go and get, but obviously you have to pay.
好的，所以“to pick something up”就是去买、去取的意思，但显然你得付钱。
All right, and he used this very interesting phrase when she was getting all these things
好的，他用了这个很有趣的说法，当她正在拿这些东西的时候。
for her.
给她。
He said, whoa, whoa, whoa, are you nuts?
他说，哇，哇，哇，你疯了吗？
Okay, so nuts is the important word here.
好，所以“nuts”是这里的关键词。
It means crazy or out of your mind.
它的意思是疯狂或失去理智。
That's right.
没错。
So it's another way of saying crazy.
所以这是说“疯狂”的另一种方式。
So if you call someone nuts or you say, he's nuts, that means.
所以如果你叫某人“nuts”，或者说“他疯了”，那意思是——
Yeah, like don't talk to him.
对，就像别跟他说话。
He's nuts.
他疯了。
Or he always says really dangerous things.
或者他总是说很危险的话。
He's nuts.
他疯了。
So he's a little bit crazy.
所以他有点疯狂。
So it's an adjective as to describe someone that's a little bit crazy or a little bit
所以这是一个形容词，用来形容有点疯狂或者有点——
adventurous maybe.
也许有点冒险的人。
But in this case, he's not actually saying she's a crazy person.
但在这种情况下，他并不是真的说她是疯子。
He's saying, listen, this is so much stuff.
他是在说，听着，这东西太多了。
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
Or he's basically saying, do you really want to do this?
或者他基本上是在说，你真的想这么做吗？
This seems like a bad decision.
这看起来是个糟糕的决定。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's why he used the phrase, are you nuts?
所以这就是为什么他用“你疯了吗？”这个说法。
Okay, so a lot of great stuff there.
好，这里有很多好东西。
Why don't we go back, listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back in a bit.
我们不如回去，最后一次听我们的对话，一会儿再回来。
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's go grab a bite to eat.
我们去吃点东西吧。
Yeah, me too.
是啊，我也是。
Oh, can we stop at the shop really fast?
哦，我们能快速去趟商店吗？
I lost my makeup bag at the airport and I want to pick up a few things.
我在机场丢了化妆包，想买点东西。
Will you take long?
会花很长时间吗？
No, five minutes.
不会，五分钟。
I promise.
我保证。
Come on, we've been here for almost an hour.
拜托，我们在这儿都快一个小时了。
I thought you said you're only going to get a few things.
我以为你只说买几样东西。
How long does it take you to pick out a lipstick and some nail polish?
你挑一支口红和指甲油要多久？
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
You have no idea what you're talking about.
你根本不知道你在说什么。
As for my eyes, I have to get eyeliner and eyelash curler, eye shadow, an eyebrow pencil
至于我的眼睛，我得买眼线笔、睫毛夹、眼影、眉笔——
and mascara.
还有睫毛膏。
Then I need to get foundation, liquid foundation.
然后我需要买粉底，液体粉底。
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇，哇，哇。
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
How much is all this going to cost?
这些总共要花多少钱？
I'm looking at the price of each one of these little things and it's outrageous.
我在看每一样小东西的价格，简直离谱。
This is basically a crayon.
这基本上就是根蜡笔。
What about you?
你呢？
You spend as much money or more on your razors, aftershave, cologne and gel.
你在剃须刀、须后水、古龙水和啫喱上花的钱一样多，甚至更多。
Not to mention how much you spend on clothes and-
更别提你在衣服上花了多少——
Fine, get the stupid $30 crayon.
好吧，买那根30美元的蠢蜡笔吧。
All right, so talking about makeup, a lot of things here.
好，所以说到化妆品，这里有很多东西。
Maybe I didn't mention a couple of things.
也许我漏掉了几样。
I don't know.
我不知道。
We took a look at the most important things, I think, right?
我们看了最重要的东西，对吧？
But you also mentioned something, for example, cover-up.
但你也提到了一个东西，比如遮瑕膏。
There's something, such makeup called cover-up.
有一种化妆品叫遮瑕膏。
Yeah, so cover-up.
对，遮瑕膏。
It could be a couple of different things in English, for example, something that you wear
在英语里，它可能指几种不同的东西，比如你在海滩上穿来——
to cover your body when you're at the beach.
遮盖身体的东西。
You don't want to walk around and everyone can see you in your bathing suit.
你不想走来走去，让所有人都看到你穿泳装的样子。
But when we're talking about makeup, a cover-up is a thing that we use to hide blemishes or
但当我们谈论化妆品时，遮瑕膏是用来遮盖瑕疵、痘痘或粉刺的东西。
zits or pimples.
You know when you get a really small red dot on your face and you're embarrassed and it's
你知道当你脸上有个很小的红点，你觉得尴尬，它很难看，你不想让别人看到吗？
ugly, and you don't want anyone to see it?
Well, cover-up is a kind of makeup you use that looks like your skin color and you put
嗯，遮瑕膏是一种化妆品，看起来像你的肤色，你涂在上面，就看不到红色了。
it on top and you can't see the red anymore.
Okay, so you cover up your pimple.
好，所以你遮盖了你的痘痘。
Yeah, or you use cover-up.
对，或者你用遮瑕膏。
It's a noun too.
它也是个名词。
Okay, and I've also seen that, well, many girls don't really wear too much lipstick
好，我还注意到，现在很多女孩不太涂口红了。
anymore nowadays.
They use this thing called lip gloss.
她们用这个叫唇彩的东西。
Okay, lip gloss.
好，唇彩。
Remember we were talking about polish earlier?
记得我们之前说过“polish”吗？
Well, gloss is a similar word.
嗯，“gloss”是一个类似的词。
It means something that makes another thing shiny.
它的意思是让别的东西变亮的东西。
And so lipstick can be very dry, can be very flat, but lip gloss is something that makes
所以口红可能很干，很平，但唇彩是让东西看起来湿润、有光泽的东西。
things look wet, makes things look shiny.
Okay, and actually one last thing before, when we talked about gel, I guess guys use
好，最后再说一件事，之前我们谈到啫喱时，我猜男生用啫喱，但女生用这个叫摩丝的东西。
gel but women use this thing called mousse.
Or they could use gel too.
或者她们也可以用啫喱。
I don't think it's gender specific, but a lot of people use mousse.
我不觉得这跟性别有关，但很多人用摩丝。
I know some men who use mousse as well.
我也知道有些男人用摩丝。
Mousse is kind of like a foam.
摩丝有点像泡沫。
You know it comes in a can and it goes ffff.
你知道它装在罐子里，一按就“噗”地出来。
Yeah, and it inflates this white substance.
对，它会膨胀成白色的东西。
Yeah, it looks like, I don't know.
是啊，看起来就像，怎么说呢。
Like whipped cream.
像打发奶油。
Like whipped cream, yeah.
像打发奶油，没错。
And you put it in your hair and it's very fluffy.
你把它抹在头发上，头发会变得很蓬松。
And it's actually less strong.
而且它其实没那么强力。
It's not like gel because if you put it in your hair, your hair won't look hard.
它不像发胶，因为如果你抹在头发上，头发不会显得硬邦邦的。
But it will help shape your hair if you want to keep your hair in one place.
但如果你想固定发型，它有助于塑形。
A lot of things here.
这里东西真多。
I think in beauty and cosmetics, we have a lot of a lot of things.
我觉得在美容和化妆品领域，我们有太多太多东西了。
And probably we didn't even touch on half of the things that are out there.
而且可能我们连市面上的一半都没讲到。
So if you have any questions or if you want to ask us anything at all about this lesson
所以如果你有任何问题，或者想就这节课问我们什么，
or anything else, you can always come to EnglishPod.com and leave your questions and comments there.
或者任何其他事情，你随时可以来EnglishPod.com留言提问。
So we'll see you at EnglishPod and until next time.
那我们EnglishPod见，下次再见。
Alright, bye everyone!
好了，大家拜拜！